rateyourmusic.com 2002-06-28

# Privacy Policy -- Rate Your Music

## rateyourmusic.com Privacy Policy

> **Rateyourmusic.com privacy policy**
> 
> rateyourmusic.com considers privacy to be a very important issue. Please read the privacy policy below to learn how we treat personally identifiable information. 
> 
> **Definition:**
> 
> when we refer to the word 'user' in this privacy policy, we refer to all people that access this web site, whether they are registered or not. The term 'registered user' refers only to users who have registered to use this service. 
> 
> **COPPA Policy:**
> 
> To comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, rateyourmusic.com will instruct users under the age of 13 not to fill out a profile, and will instruct users under the age of 13 to choose a username that does not contain the user's name or other identifyable information. In addition, users under the age of 13 are instructed not to use any personally identifyable information in any public review or message board posting. Users under 13 may fully participate in this web service if they receive permission from their parents, and the parent(s) send an e-mail to sharifi@cc.gatech.edu that states that they have read this privacy policy and give permission for their child to use the service. If a user under the age of 13 fills out a profile despite instructions not to, the information stored in the profile will be removed. 
> 
> **What information we collect:**
> 
> Upon registration, rateyourmusic.com asks users who would like to register, and are over 13 years of age, to fill out a short profile. The profile is an optional step of registration. The following information is collected from registration and profiles: 
> 
> Username and Password  
>  First and Last Name  
>  Age  
>  Sex  
>  Location  
>  Zip Code  
>  E-Mail Address  
>  Personal homepage  
>  Favorite Musical Artist/Bands  
>  Any other comments the user wishes to make about him/herself 
> 
> Users can put anything in the location field that they wish. 
> 
> In addition, registered users may add albums to their collection, give the album a rating, write reviews or biographies, and make public postings on message boards/forums. 
> 
> **What information other users of the website can see:**
> 
> If the user provides this information, other users can see his/her username, name, age, sex, the text that the user typed in the location field, homepage, favorite bands and artists, and other comments. In addition, other users will be able to see the albums that are part of the user's lists, as well as the ratings and reviews of those albums. 
> 
> The user's e-mail address is visible to other users if they wish to share it by checking the box that says "Check here if you would like your e-mail address to be visible to other users of this site." , which is unchecked by default. 
> 
> The user's zip code is NOT visible to other users. 
> 
> **What we do with this information:**
> 
> rateyourmusic.com allows users to provide this personal information so that the other users can learn more about them. 
> 
> rateyourmusic.com does not use your name, the text typed in the location field, homepage, favorite bands, and other comments in any way other than to display them to other users. 
> 
> rateyourmusic.com ONLY uses e-mail addresses to mail the user's password back to them if they request this service, and to allow other users to contact the user. 
> 
> rateyourmusic.com will eventually use the sex, age, and zip code of users to display aggregate statistics to users. For example, when choosing an album, we would like to tell you what percentage of males and females gave it a high rating, what the average age of the owners of the album is, and what areas of the United States the album is popular in. 
> 
> rateyourmusic.com does not and will not sell information about you to third parties. If rateyourmusic provides a link to another web site, and that web site asks for personally identifyable information, this information is not shared with rateyourmusic. 
> 
> **Other types of information:**
> 
> rateyourmusic.com uses cookies. We use cookies to allow the user to stay logged in while he/she uses the service. In addition, we keep track of the last time the user visited, so that we may alert a user of new services/features since his/her last visit, as well as to find out how many people are returning to our site. We do not use cookies for any reason other than these 2 purposes. 
> 
> rateyourmusic.com's web server collects the IP address, page requested, and referral page when you access this web site. 
> 
> Occasionally, web sites receive accesses from a user, in which the user is attempting to disrupt the operation of a web service or its users. In this case, we may review our server logs to find the IP address and block access from that person/computer and/or report the incident to the user's Internet service provider. This is the only manner in which IP addresses are used on this site. 
> 
> We receive referral information when a user clicks on a link to rateyourmusic.com from another website. The website that he/she was visiting before rateyourmusic.com appears in the server log. We may use this information to find out what websites or search engines are linking to our web site, and/or what keywords are being typed into search engines to cause our page to appear in the results of the search. 
> 
> The page requested may be used to determine the most popular sections of our web service. 
> 
> We do not share the information gathered from cookies, ip addresses, referrals, or pages requested with anyone. 
> 
> We will comply with all federal, state, and local laws if asked to give personal information to legal authorities. 
> 
> **Changes to this Privacy Policy:**
> 
> If rateyourmusic.com makes any changes to this privacy policy, a notice will appear on the front page of our web site. 
> 
> **Questions or Suggestions:**
> 
> If you have any questions about this privacy policy, or would like to make a suggestion, please click [here](http://rateyourmusic.com/suggestions/subject=Privacy%20Policy). 

* * *

Search For in   
*Search Tip: just enter a few letters of the artist/album you're searching for.
